<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<Record><Version>Record_v1.0.xsd</Version><RecordID>518663419</RecordID><DateTimeStamp>20151210173645</DateTimeStamp><ActionCode>change</ActionCode><RecordTitle>Budget Chop Ends Funds</RecordTitle><Publication><PublicationID>105359</PublicationID><Title>Boston Globe (1960-1984)</Title><Qualifier>Boston, Mass.</Qualifier></Publication><Publisher>New York Times Company</Publisher><AlphaPubDate>Apr 24, 1966</AlphaPubDate><NumericPubDate>19660424</NumericPubDate><SourceType>Historical Newspapers</SourceType><ObjectType>Feature</ObjectType><ObjectType>Article</ObjectType><Contributor><ContribRole>Author</ContribRole><LastName>Ayres</LastName><FirstName>James</FirstName><PersonName>James Ayres</PersonName><OriginalForm>JAMES AYRES</OriginalForm></Contributor><LanguageCode>ENG</LanguageCode><StartPage>91</StartPage><URLDocView>http://search.proquest.com/docview/518663419/</URLDocView><Products><Product><ProductID>1007871</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1007945</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1008891</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009043</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>1009131</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000046</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product><Product><ProductID>10000227</ProductID><HasFullText>true</HasFullText></Product></Products><Abstract>                                                                                                A dollar-for-dollar matching agreement between the state and its communities for buying land for conservation and recreation purposes has been broken by both the House and Senate Ways and Means Committees.                         </Abstract><FullText>                                                                                                Budget Chop Ends Funds                 Local Conservation Money Won&apos;t Be Matched by State                 By JAMES AYRES                 Globe Conservation Resorter                 dollar-for-dollar match Ing agreement between the state and its communities for buying land for conservation and recreation purposes has been broken by both the House and Senate Ways and Means Committees                 Both committees have quietly scratched 200 000                 from deficiency budget preI sented by Gov Volpe to continue                 the self-help land                 ANALYSIS                 quisition program begun by thh state in 1961 to protect key open apace against steady encroachment by developers                 Jules Sussman of Lexington chairman of the Massachusetts Assn of Conservation Commissions which represents those of more than 240 communities across the state said the Legislature&apos;s failure to fund the program could spell the end of the conservation commission movement In Massachusetts                 Sussman said 700 000 originally requested by the Department of Natural Resources is needed to carry out the program this year                 department spokesman said There Isn&apos;t one cent in the til for the program now                 The decision by the Ways and Means Committees has left 27 communities to face bill of 514 647 representing the amount the department of Natural Resources would pay them if the Legislature approved the department s budget request                 Those are Amherst Athol &apos;Barnstable Bedford Braintree                 Chelmsford Dedham Dennis Easton Franklin Grafton Harwich Hopedale Hudson Leicester Lexing ton Lunenburg North Reading Norton Paxton Rehoboth Sandwich Shrewsbury West -Bridgewater Westport Whitman and Wilbraham                 In addition there are at least eight other towns which voted in the March town meetings to buy open space and the department expects to receive requests for matching grants from them shortly                 Those are Bourne Dover Pepperell Seekonk Sharon and Whitman the last still waiting for money for previous project                 Sussman said It was hard to understand how the Legislature could fail to support the program especially with the eligibility this year for the first time of 39 cities and towns in the Metropolitan District Commission parks district for state matching grants for the purchase of open and recreation                 Previously the state match ing funds were raised through                 bond Issue which was paid for by cities and towns outside the parks district leaving metropolitan Boston                 ineligible for the funds                 The Dept of Natural Resources sought this year an appropriation of 700 000 from the local aid fund so that communities would be eligible the department feeling that It was most important to develop recreation and open space In highly developed metropolitan Boston                 What concerns Sussman is -ot only the veto on the state s share of the program but also the tremendous embarrassment to conservation commission members on the local level which might result in discrediting the entire movement                 In Easton for example the Town Meeting approved the purchase of 278 acres of ponds pine groves fields woods and trails after the local conservation commission had informed                 ... IT COULD HAPPEN HERE IN MASSACHUSETTS.                 it that Easton&apos;s share of the $160,000 project would be only $40,000.                 Under legislation passed in 1965, the Federal government will pick up half the tab ($80,000) and the state and town would split the remaining bill.                 (The Federal government will also give 50 percent aid for taking developed land for recreation and open space uses in highly developed areas such as Boston, which could cut acquisition costs to 25 percent for the city if the state matching funds were forthcoming.)                 The faces of the members of Easton&apos;s conservation commission have turned bright red after being notified that the state s self help treasury was empty and that this year s appropriation had been trimmed to zero.                 Conservationists feel that the Legislature&apos;s action seems inexcusable in the face of reports by consultants to the Dept. of Natural Resources and by the Metropolitan Area                 Planning Council, which provides guidelines for the growth of metropolitan Boston, that the state s open space and recreation areas will have to quadruple by                 1977 to meet the people s I needs.                 A report by the M.A.P.C. in December warned that the benefits of open space &quot;which are becoming more and more important in this era of rapid urbanization are clearly being denied to the majority of the Boston region.&quot;                 The study urged public purchase of 200,000 acres of land and water in eastern Massachusetts, where two thirds of the state s 5.5 million people live.                 The Legislature doesn&apos;t seem to be getting the message this year, and it didn&apos;t get it last year.                 In 1965, the department submitted a bill to increase the land transfer tax on the sale of real estate by 45 cents on each $1000.                 The bil earmarked 20 percent of the tax money raised                 for the department, and of- I                 ficials predicted they would receive $700,000 a year to pass on to the cities and towns to acquire land.                 The bill was presented during the battle over the sales tax, and the conservation measure was stripped from the bill, turning it into  revenue-raising legislation.                 The bill died along with 600 others when the Legislature was forced to adjourn in Jan.                 Sussman said the Massachusetts Conservation Council, which represents conservation-oriented organizations across the state, will meet at the Museum of Science on Wednesday afternoon to discuss what he feels is the state s major conservation crisis.                 He said Massachusetts was the first state in the nation to establish conservation commissions in 1959 and that subsequent enabling legislation gave them the authority to plan for the proper use of natural resources and acquire land on the local level.                 Several states have copied Massachusetts and have funded their acquisition programs to a far greater extent than Massachusetts has, Sussman said.                 &quot;Across the nation, people now understand the need for open space in their own communities rather than 50 or 100 miles away.&quot;                 Sussman predicts that the movement may sputter to a halt if the state does not pro-                         </FullText></Record>